>> Hi. I'm Leah Manning.
For my comp class, I'm writing a paper on
copyright laws and why they have to change
because of digital networks, which make it
a lot easier for people to exchange text.
So this book that I found argues that current
copyright law gets in the way of creativity.
And it is called "Moral Panics
and the Copyright Wars."
I liked this book a lot.
It is written by a copyright
lawyer, which helps,
so it was a pretty good source for my paper.
Anyway, when I was using this
book for my MLA work cited list,
I was just going over how I
should find and everything.
So, for me, I have a cover on my book, so my
title and author aren't wonderfully lifted,
but if you don't have a cover, or it's just
really dirty, you can turn to the title page,
which, again, will have the
title and the author's name.
The first thing you need is the
author, and his name is right here.
Pretty easy to spell.
You put the last name first, first name
last, and then a period after that.
Next, you're going to move to
the title, and an important thing
to remember there is you're only supposed
to capitalize the important words.
So, like, here, I'm not going to capitalize
any of the articles or conjunctions
and just keep the important words there.
And after I type that up, put a period.
Next thing I have to look for
is the place it was published,
so I turn the page, and here it is.
Really small print and there's a
bunch of different cities listed here.
If that happens, just pick the first one.
So for me, that is Oxford.
I am not going to write that Oxford is in
England because any academic reader should know
that Oxford is in England, so I'm going
to write Oxford and then put a colon.
Now, I have to look for the publisher.
The publisher is right up here
at the very top of the page.
It says Oxford University Press.
However, I'm not going to write
out the words University Press.
I am going to write a capital U and a
capital P. that stands for University Press,
and every academic reader will know that.
So my citation for the publisher
will say Oxford UP.
And then I will put a comma.
And now I'm going to look for the year.
Usually, it's really easy, and there is
a little copyright symbol and the year.
But in my case, that didn't happen.
I looked, couldn't find it, took it to a
professor who pointed out to me the Library
of Congress Cataloging and
Publication Data -- long words.
Yeah, I know.
What it is is that the Library of Congress
is the official library of the United States,
and it is their job to make sure they have
track of all new important literature.
So to make that easier for them,
they put together this data.
All of this is the standardized
information about the book.
And at the very end is a number.
That number is called the Library of Congress
control number, and the first four digits happen
to be the year of publication for the book.
So I find that year.
For me, it is 2009.
So after the year, you put a period.
You think you're at the end of
the your citation, but you're not.
You have to write the medium in
which your citation was written.
So for me, it's obviously print.
So I put the word print, a period, and
I'm officially done with my citation.
So I hope my little foray into
citation will help you out on yours.
Good luck.