>> Hi there.
I'm Gabriel Vatova [assumed spelling].
I'm finishing a required paper
for a class on research writing.
I've been interested in the ethics of how
photographs are used online, and so I was happy
to find this article in the "New York Times."
It's about how parents want to put their
kids' pictures online so grandparents can see,
but then the parents get angry and surprised
when they learn the pictures are used
in advertisements without their permission.
To make this citation, I followed
the MLA pattern for web pages.
And so, like with any citation in MLA
format, I began with the author's name,
putting the last name first,
and then his first name.
The author's name is pretty small
here, but it was easy to find.
I was real careful about
spelling this man's last name.
I don't know how to pronounce it
-- Krenka [assumed spelling] --
but I wanted to be sure I got it right.
And then I put the title of
the article on the web page.
The title was pretty easy to find here.
It's nice and big.
And I put the title inside quotation marks
because this is an article in
a periodical and not a book.
Then I put the name of the website, which
on this web page is easy to see at the top.
Website titles usually are at
the top left of a web page.
In the citation, the name of
the website goes in italics,
and I left out the "the"
at the front of the name.
You can leave off "a" or "the"
from website titles in MLA style.
Next comes the name of the publisher.
If this is on a web page, it's
either at the top or the very bottom.
You just have to look.
In this case, the name is at the very bottom
and is the same as the name of the website.
So I put "New York Times" into
the citation a second time.
This time, though, it's not
italicized, and, like, before,
I leave off the "the" at the front.
And when you put the name of a publisher in
MLA style, you can leave off company, too.
Next comes the date that
the article was published.
The "New York Times" makes
this pretty easy to find.
They put it right under the author's name.
I had to remember to put the date in the format
that MLA style wants with the date first,
then the month in the abbreviation the
MLA wants, and then, finally, the year.
But if you can't find a full date
and month and year on a website,
you should just put the month
and the year, or just the year.
And if you can't find any
date, put ND for "no date."
Then I put the medium, web, and the date that I
accessed the web page, again, in the same format
at the date the web page was published.
I always go back and check the punctuation
in my citations to be sure I got it right.
In citations like this one, you have to
put a period after each separate element,
except that there's a comma
after the publisher's name
and quotation marks around the article title.
And then the periodical name
needs to be in italics.
I sometimes forget to put a period at the
end, so I always have to double-check that.