>> Hello, my name is Jerro Sand [assumed
spelling], and today, I'm working on a paper
for an econ class about how
nutritional information
on packaging affects people's food purchases.
So I was really happy when I found this
article about how parents mostly want
to buy healthy food for their families, but
their decision is based on the cost of the food
and whether or not they're being
distracted by their kids while shopping.
I found a PDF of this article on the
database of my college library website.
I'm following the APA format for a periodical,
but then I have to add additional information
that comes along with finding
this article online.
As with any citation in APA format,
I put the author's name first.
In the article, there are three authors.
Science and social science articles
often have a couple of authors,
which is always a bit of a pain to type.
You've got to put the author's first
-- the first author's last name first,
and then that person initials, including
two initials if two names are given.
But luckily, in this article, these
authors only use their first names.
Then you would do the same for its second
author, and then the same for a third author.
And when you do this, you've got to keep
all the commas and periods all straight,
a period after each initial and then
a comma before each new last name.
At least AP lets you put an ampersand
before the last author's name instead
of having to spell the word "and."
You can find the ampersand
on your keyboard by holding
down your shift key and pressing
the number seven.
Then in parenthesis, you put the
year the article was published.
So right here, this article
was published in 2009.
Next in an APA citation, you put the
article's title in quotation marks.
Here, the article's title is "An Exploration
of parents' food purchasing behaviours."
Only the first word of the title gets
capitalized, as seen here, and if there's colon
in the middle of the title, the first word
after the colon also gets capitalized.
And notice how I kept this
British spelling of "behaviours"
since that's how it appears in the title.
So when you cite your source, you have
to spell the title exactly how
it's spelled in the article.
Then comes the periodical's name in italics.
"Appetite" is the title of this journal.
A comma goes after the periodical name, followed
by the volume number of this particular journal.
The volume number for this particular
journal is 53, found right here.
It's following the periodical name.
The volume number goes right
after the periodical name
in the citation, and it is in italics, too.
If there were an issue date, it would be --
it would go into parenthesis
following the volume number,
but because there is no other number
in this information at the very top
of the page, I can leave out an issue date.
The page numbers come next.
It's awfully sweet of this periodical
to put the page numbers here
at the very top of the page, too.
If I had found a print -- found this
article in the print version of the journal,
I'd be done now, but now
I have to add information
about having found the article online.
At the very end goes this
digital object identifier.
This number is usually somewhere on the first
page of an online periodical, but you often have
to look a bit in this periodical.
It's way down at the bottom.
Here in this article, it's down at the lower
left-hand corner of the article right here.
I like this idea of digital
object identifier code
so that we can always find an article
online even if someone moves it around.
The thing I always forget is that there is no
period after the digital object identifier.
I worked hard to remember always to put a period
at the end of a citation, but you can't put one
with a digital object identifier because
people would think the period was a part
of the identifier, and it's not, so no period.
And that's it.
I'm done with this citation.
I only have six more to do
before I can go to bed.
Thank you.