>> Phoebe [assumed spelling]: Hi.
I'm Phoebe.
I'm writing a paper for an education
class, and I got interested in how violence
in society affects student learning.
The U.S. Government has some great
resources about aspects of education here.
And I found one website attached
to the Department of Education
that is all about statistics in education.
I found a report about school crime.
And it has information in it about
how fear of violence affects students.
Because this report is a non-periodical,
it isn't published weekly or monthly.
I'm following the APA pattern
for non-periodicals.
And then adding the online
information at the end.
Because there's no named author for
the report, I start with the name
of the responsible government agency.
There's a lot of different
names on this website,
but the one at the top left that's biggest
is also what's named in the website's URL.
So that's a good sign of
who is most responsible.
So for this citation, I'm
putting National Center
for Education Statistics with a period after it.
The date is easy to find here at the top right.
Even though the information is about
2008, the report was published in 2009.
So I put the date in parentheses
after the responsible agency.
And add a period.
Then I put the report title in italics just
like any other non-periodical like a book.
Only the first word gets capitalized,
and then there's a period at the end.
Down at the bottom of the webpage,
I found the place of publication.
Washington, DC.
The other names back at the top of the
page tell who published this report.
And I need to be careful to get them all.
Finally, this website doesn't provide any
digital object identifier for this report.
So I have to copy the URL and
paste it into my citation.
I sometimes forget to put retrieved from in
front of the URL, but I remembered this time.
And I also remembered not to put a period
after the URL since that could confuse people
and make them think they should type a period
when they enter the URL to look at this source.
And that's it.